# **Juan Bracho**

Dallas, TX 75211 | (214) 817 6960 | LinkedIn | juanbracho16@gmail.com |

## **Summary**

Bilingual legal professional with MA in Corporate Law. Experience drafting, reviewing, and negotiating legal contracts in Spanish. Extensive knowledge of legal terminology in both Spanish and English. Cross-cultural awareness and experience working with teams remotely, across time zones, in both Spanish and English. Experience with both project management, SaaS, and administrative tasks.

## **Experience**

August 2022 - .

#### ECC Retention Specialist II | State Farm, Richardson, USA.

- Conducted client changes to policies and questions in English and Spanish.
- Performed changes to additions, and reinstatements of Auto and Fire Policies.

October 2020 - September 2021.

#### Project Administrator | Avaya Argentina, Buenos Aires, Argentina.

- Resource management and allocation, including tracking of both hours and expenses.
- Calendar management for multiple project leaders and staff.
- Sent invoices to clients and filed bills for contractors.
- Elaboration of project overview for use of resources, profit and drafted summary report.
- Team member for 2021 ISO9001 Internal Auditing process.
- Worked with teams in Spanish and English.
- SaaS experience via Avaya One Cloud CCaaS, Avaya Spaces, and Avaya OneCloud.

June 2019 - May 2020.

#### Store Manager | Mascotas de la Abadía, Buenos Aires, Argentina.

- Supply chain management including tracking inventory, ordering from suppliers, and negotiating supplier contracts for three stores.
- Conducted client consultations in Spanish and English.
- Tracked expenses and profit including management of cash for three stores.
- Data analysis via Excel including sales projection and per-product sale comparisons across stores.

Jan 2018 – June 2018.

#### Intern | MYRO Associates, Maracaibo, Venezuela.

- Drafted contracts and Power of Attorney documents in Spanish.
- Managed relationships with notary and apostille offices used by MYRO Associates.
- Formed part of the team working with the Refugee Education Trust, an affiliate of the UNHCR.
- Met with clients and answered inquiries as they related to issues of compliance and paperwork preparation for requesting government permissions.

### **Education**

Universidad Argentina de la Empresa (UADE), Buenos Aires, Argentina.

- April 2020 to November 2021
- Master of Arts in Business Law.
- GPA: 7.4/10
- Relevant Coursework: Corporate Governance; Conflict Resolution Mechanisms, Litigation and Business; Corporate Tax Law; Business Accounting; Corporate Social Responsibility.

Universidad Rafael Urdaneta (URU), Maracaibo, Venezuela.

- May 2014 to September 2018
- Bachelor of Arts in Law.
- GPA: 14.4/20
- Relevant Coursework: Civil Law (7 courses); Civil Procedure (4 courses); Commercial Law (4 courses);
  Criminal Law (2 courses); International Private Law (2 courses); International Public Law (2 courses).

### **Skills**

- Bilingual: Spanish (Native) English (Full Working Proficiency)
- Microsoft Office Full Working Proficiency including use of Excel Pivot tables.
- SaaS experience via Avaya Systems.
- Python, MySQL, JavaScript, CSS, NodeJS. Basic.
- Google Certificate: Google Analytics.
- Actively taking additional courses in Data Analysis related to best practices and principles for data management, and Big Data.